A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, Office Files of Ellen Brown FA510
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, Office Files of Ellen Brown
1998-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Brown, Ellen L.
Ford Foundation
FA510
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Subject files.
Biographical / Historical
Ellen Brown is a development finance specialist, entrepreneur, and former program officer at the Ford Foundation. Brown started at the Ford Foundation as a Program Investment Officer in its Program Related Investments Program (PRI) in the late 1980s. Then she moved to the Foundation's South Africa and Namibia Program where she was based as a Program Officer at the Johannesburg, South Africa office. In 1998, she became a Program Officer in the Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development unit. She stayed in that position until she left the Foundation in 2000.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Brown worked as Director of Strategic Initiatives at the New Jersey Institute for Social Justice. She later opened her own business, the Doll Loft which sells doll making kits. Brown earned an M.B.A. from Columbia University.
- Subject Files, 1998-2000; I
  - ACENET, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - American Small Business Alliance, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Richard -- SME Research, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Brody and Weiser - CDFI Study Report, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Bosworth, Brian -- Regional Business Civic, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Cal Meadow, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Center for the New West, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Churchill, Craig -- Insurance Project, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Cluster Study, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Community Development Venture Capital Alliance (CDVCA), 1999 (Box 1)
  - Community Reinvestment Fund, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Ecotrust, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Ecotrust, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Enterprise Corporation of the Delta, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Fishman, Bob, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Futureworks, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Georgia Institute of Technology, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Micro Loans Regulatory Council, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Nigeria Electronic Communications, 1999 (Box 1)
  - NorthEast Ventures, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Prince of Wales Business Leaders Forum, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Shorebank Advisory Services, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Shorebank Cleveland, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Shorebank Cleveland -- Legal/Closing, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Small Enterprise Assistance Funds, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Steel Valley Authority, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Sustainable Jobs Fund, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Women's Emerging Markets Equity Fund, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Women's World Banking, 1999 (Box 1)